Sync by
지노
jin5a@naver.com
해리 포터와 죽음의 성물 2부
[자유로운 집요정 '도비' 여기 잠들다]
It's beautiful here.
참 예쁜 곳이네
It was our aunt뭩. We used to come here as kids.
우리 고모 집이야
어릴 때 가끔 놀러왔었는데
The Order uses it now as a safe house.
지금은 불사조 기사단의 안전가옥이고
What's left of us at least.
이제 안전한 곳은 여기밖에 없어
머글들은 이게 귀신을 쫓는다고 믿는대
Muggles think these
things keep evil away.
잘못된 미신같지만
But they're wrong.
그 도깨비를 만나봐야겠어
I need to talk to the Goblin.
좀 어때?
How are you?
살아는 있지
Alive.
- 기억 안 나는구나?
- 네가 처음 그린고트에 왔을 때 말인가?
You probably don't remember that you--
--That I showed you to your vault,
the first time you came to Gringotts.
넌 도깨비들 사이에서도 유명인사야, 해리 포터
Even amongst Goblins, you are famous
Harry Potter.
- 그 요정을 묻어주었나?
- 그래
- You buried the elf?
- Yes.
그리고 나를 여기에 데려왔지
And brought me here.
You are...
너는‥‥
보기 드문 마법사야.... 안 그래?
Pretty unusual, is it?
저 칼은 어떻게 가져왔지?
How did you come by the sword?
말하자면 길어
It's complicated.
왜 벨라트릭스가 금고에
칼을 보관하고 있었던 거지?
Why did Bellatrix Lestrange think
it should be in her vault at Gringotts?
말하자면 길어
It's complicated.
이 칼은 필요로 하는 사람에게 가도록 되어 있어
우리가 훔친 건 아니니까
The sword presented itself to us,
in moment of need.
We didn't steal it.
레스트랭 부인의 금고에
똑같은 모양의 칼이 있지
There is a sword in Madam Lestrange's vault
identical to this one.
하지만 그건 가짜거든
But it is a fake.
- 지난 여름까진 가짜가 금고에 있었어
- 벨라트릭스는 그게 가짜인 줄 몰랐겠군
It was placed there this past summer.
And she never suspected it was a fake.
진짜처럼 감쪽같지
오직 도깨비만이 진품을 알아 볼수 있어
The replica is very convincing.
Only a goblin would recognize that this is the true Sword of Gryffindor.
벨라트릭스가 누구한테서 얻은 거지?
Who is the acquaintance?
호그와트의 교수였지
지금은 교장이라더군
A Hogwarts Professor.
As I understand that he's now Headmaster.
스네이프?
Snape.
스네이프가 벨라트릭스의 금고에
가짜 칼을 넣었군
He put a fake sword in Bellatrix's vault.
- 왜지?
- 그린고트의 금고에는 신기한 것들이 많지
Why?
There are more than a few curious things
in the vaults at Gringotts.
레스트랭의 금고도 마찬가지일 거고?
And in Madam Lestrange's vault as well?
Perhaps.
어쩌면‥‥
벨라트릭스의 금고 안에 들어가야겠어
I need to get into Gringotts.
Into one of the vaults.
불가능해
- It is impossible.
- Alone, yes.
혼자서는 안되지만
당신이랑 가면 할 수 있어
But with you, no.
왜 널 도와야 하지?
- Why should I help you?
- I have gold.
나한텐 금이 아주 많아
Lots of it.
금 따위엔 관심 없어
I've no interest in gold.
그럼 뭘 바라지?
Then what?
저 칼
That.
저거면 괜찮을 듯 한데
That is my price.
Are you thinking there's a Horcrux in Bellatrix's vault?
금고에 호크룩스가 있는게 확실해?
벨라트릭스가 칼을 보자마자
갑자기 당황해서 어쩔 줄 몰라했잖아
Well, she was terrified when she thought we had been in there.
She kept asking you,
what else was taken?
분명 호크룩스는 거기에 있어
I bet you anything, there's Horcrux in there.
Another piece of his soul.
- 그걸 찾아야만 그 자를 없앨 수 있다고
- 우리가 호크룩스를 찾으면, 그 다음은?
Let's find it, kill it, and we are
one step closer to killing him.
And what happens when we find it,
저 놈한테 칼을 줘 버리면
호크룩스는 뭘로 부술 건데?
How're we supposed to destroy it, now you're giving the sword to Griphook?
고민 좀 해봐야지
I'm still working on that part.
많이 편찮으셔
He's weak.
누구요?
Who?
올리밴더씨
Mr. Ollivander
몇 가지 질문이 있어요
I need to ask you a few questions.
무엇이든 물어보렴, 얘야
Anything, m'boy.
Anything!
이 지팡이 좀 봐주세요
제가 이걸 써도 되는지 궁금해서요
Would you mind identifying this wand?
We need to know if it's safe to use.
Uhh... Walnut
호두나무랑‥‥
용의 심장 털로 만들었군
Dragon Heartstring
23cm 정도에‥‥
12 and three quarter inches.
단단하군
Unyie...
아주 단단해
Unyielding.
벨라트릭스 레스트랭의 지팡이군
This belonged to Bellatrix Lestrange.
조심해서 다루거라
이것도 봐주실래요?
And this?
산사나무랑
Hawthorn.
유니콘의 털로 만들었군
An unicorn hair.
25cm에‥‥
10 inches.
탄력성도 적당해
Reasonably pliant.
이 지팡이의 예전 주인은
드레이코 말포이였군
This was the wand of Draco Malfoy.
예전 주인이라구요?
Was?
지금은 아닌가요?
Is it not still?
그렇단다
네가 이걸 뺏은 것 같구나
Well, perhaps not.
If you won it from him.
주인이 바뀐 걸 느낄 수 있어
I sense its allegiance has changed.
말씀하신대로 라면
You talk about wands,
as if they have feelings...
지팡이가 감정을 갖고 있다는건가요
마치.... 생각을 할 수 있는 것처럼요
.......can think!
지팡이가 마법사를 선택하는 거라네, 포터 군
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
나처럼 평생 지팡이만 연구해 온
사람들에겐 불변의 진리지
That much has always been clear to
those of us who've studied wandlore.
그럼 혹시 죽음의 성물에 대해
들어 본 적 있으신가요?
And, what do you know about the Deathly Hallows?
소문에는 세 가지가 존재한다고 하지
It is rumored there are three.
딱총나무 지팡이,
적으로부터 몸을 숨겨주는 투명 망토
The Elder Wand, the Cloak of Invisibility,
to hide you from your enemies...
그리고 사랑하는 사람을 되살리는
부활의 돌이 있지
and the Resurrection Stone, to bring
back loved ones from the dead.
그 세 가지를 모두 가지면
죽음을 지배할 수 있다더구나
Together, they make one the Master of Death.
하지만 그 성물이 진짜라고
믿는 사람은 거의 없단다
But few, truly believe that such objects exist.
당신은요?
Do you?
그게 존재한다고 믿으시나요?
Do you believe they exist, sir?
글쎄‥‥
Well...
그런 오랜 전설을 믿을 이유가 있을까?
I see no reason to put
stock into an old wives' tale.
거짓말을 하시는군요
You're lying!
하나는 알고 계시잖아요
You know one exists.
그 자에게 딱총나무 지팡이가
어디 있는지 말해주셨잖아요
You told him about it.
You told him about the Elder Wand...
그리고 그 자는 그걸 찾으러 갔죠
and where he could go looking for it.
그가 날 고문했어
He tortured me.
게다가‥‥
Besides...
난 그저 들리는 소문을 알려줬을 뿐이야
....I only conveyed rumors.
정말‥‥
There's...
정말로 거기 있다고는 생각도 못했단다
There's no telling whether he will find it.
그 자가 찾아냈어요
He has found it, sir.
푹 쉬세요
We'll let you rest.
그 자는 자넬 쫓고 있어, 포터 군
He's after you, Mr. Potter.
만약 그 자가 정말
딱총나무 지팡이를 찾았다면
If it's true what you say,
that he has the Elder Wand,
안됐지만....
자네는 그를 이길 수 없을거라네
I'm afraid,
...you really don't stand a chance.
그럼 그가 절 찾기 전에
제가 먼저 죽여야겠군요
Well, I suppose I'll have to kill him,
before he finds me, then.
정말 벨라트릭스의 머리카락이야?
You're sure that's hers?
확실해
Positive.
그래서‥‥
Well?
나 어때 보여?
How do I look?
끔찍하다‥‥
Hideous.
칼은 헤르미온느에게 맡겨
You can give that to Hermione to hold.
Alright, Griphook?
우린 너만 믿고 있어
호크룩스만 찾으면 칼은 네 거야
We're relying on you, Griphook.
If you get us past the guards into the vault...
The sword's yours.
안녕하십니까, 레스트랭님
Madam Lestrange.
좋은 아침
Good morning.
좋은 아침이라고? 좋은 아침?!
그 따위로 하다간 단번에 들켜버릴거야
Good morning?
You're Bellatrix Lestrange,
not some school girl!
Hey!
Easy!
- 진정해
- 잡힐 바엔 차라리 죽는게 낫다고! 알아들어?
If she gives us away, we must swear
to use that sword to slit our own throats.
Understand?
그립훅 말이 맞아
내가 잘못했어
No, he's right.
I speak stupid.
괜찮아
계속 움직이자
Okay.
Let's do it.
금고에 들어가고 싶구나
I wish to enter my vault.
신분을 밝히시죠
Identification?
나한테 그게 중요한가?
I hardly think that would be necessary.
아, 레스트랭 부인
Madam Lestrange.
기다리게 하지 마
I don't like to be kept waiting.
눈치 챈 것 같아
I know...
They know she's an impostor.
뒤에 경비원이 온다
They'd be warned.
해리, 이제 어떡해?
Harry...
What do we do, Harry?
레스트랭 부인, 지팡이를 봐도 되겠습니까?
Madam Lestrange,
would you mind presenting your wand?
내가 왜?
And why should I do that?
신분 확인 절차이니 협조 부탁드립니다
It's the bank's policy!
I'm sure you understand, given current climate.
내가 싫다는데
감히 날 거역하겠다는 거야?
No! I most certainly do not understand!
죄송하지만 꼭 확인해야겠습니다
I'm afraid, I must insist.
"임페리오"!
Imperio!
좋습니다
따라오십시오
Very well, Madam Lestrange.
If you will follow me?
저게 뭐지?
What is that, Griphook?
앞에 폭포야!
Griphook!
Aresto Momentum
"아레스토 모멘텀"!
잘했어, 헤르미온느
Well done, Hermione.
너희들 분장 마법이 풀렸잖아
Oh no, you two're like you again.
도둑 방지용 폭포야
마법을 씻어내는 거지
The Thief's Downfall,
washes away all enchantments.
Can be deadly.
여기서 빠져나가는 길은 없나?
You don't say.
Just out of interest,
is there any other way out of here?
없어
No.
잠깐, 너희들 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
What the devil are all you doing down here?
도둑들이군!
Thieves!
- 네놈들을 그냥‥‥
- "임페리오"!
You gave up the.....
-Imperio
-You!
기분 나쁜 소리네
That doesn't sound good.
맙소사!
용이잖아?
Bloody hell!
That's an Ukrainian Ironbelly.
이걸 들어
Here.
이 소리를 들으면
고통 받도록 훈련 되어있거든
It's been trained to expect pain
when it hears the noise.
너무 야만적이야
That's barbaric!
"루모스"
Lumos
이야‥‥
Blimey!
"아씨오 호크룩스"
Accio Horcrux
저번에도 실패했으면서 또 하냐?
You seem you're gonna try
that one to get over here?
여기선 어떤 주문도 안 통해
No kind of magic would work in here.
해리, 여기 있는 것 같아?
It's in here, Harry?
뭐라도 느껴져?
Can you feel anything?
저기 있다!
저 위에!
That's it!
Up there!
건들면 복제되도록 주문을 걸어놨군
They have added the Gemino curse.
Everything you touch will multiply.
칼을 줘!
Give me the sword.
건들지 마, 론!
Stop moving!
Do it!
- We had deal, Griphook!
- The cup for the sword!
잔을 준다고 했잖아!
칼부터 내놔!
난 너희를 들여보내준다고만 했지
내보내준다곤 안했어
I said I'll get you in,
I didn't say anything about getting you out.
멈춰!
Griphook! Thieves!
Griphook!
Hey, thieves!
도둑이다!
저 녀석을 이용해서 나가자
Is that okay?
We've still got Bogrod.
헉..지지리 운도 없네
That's unfortunate.
뭐 좋은 방법 없어?
We can't just stand here,
You got any idea?
- 네가 제일 똑똑하잖아
- 넌 생각한 거 있어?
You're the brilliant one.
있긴 한데 너무 무모해
I've got something,
but it's mad!
"리덕토"!
Reducto
뭐 하고 있어?
Well, come on, then!
Relashio
Keep moving!
- 뭐라도 해봐!
- "리덕토"!
Now what?
Reducto
꽉 잡아!
Hold on.
최고야!
환상이었어!
That was brilliant!
Absolutely brilliant!
내려야겠어!
We're dropping!
- I say we jump!
- When?
뛰어내린다고?
- 언제?
- 지금!
Now!
그가 알고 있어
He knows.
우리가 그린고트에
갔던 걸 알고 있어
You-Know-Who.
He knows we broke into Gringotts.
호크룩스를 찾아다니는 것도 알고 있고
He knows what we took,
and he knows we're hunting Horcruxes.
그걸 어떻게 알아?
- How is it you know?
- I saw him.
그 자를 봤어
또 그의 머릿속을 엿봤구나!
해리, 그러면 안되잖아!
You let him in?
Harry, you can't do that!
Hermione, I can't always help it!
나도 보고 싶어서 본 게 아냐
마음대로 할수있는게 아니라고
Well, maybe I can.
I don't know!
Never mind!
What happened?
그럼 이제 어떻게 되는 거야?
Well, he's angry...
그 자는 분노하면서도 두려워하고 있어
호크룩스가 없어지면 제 목숨이 위태로우니까
and scared too.
He knows, if we find and destroy
all the Horcruxes, we'll be able to kill him.
I reckon he'll stop at nothing
to make sure we don't find the rest.
우리가 나머지를 찾을 때까지
그도 가만 있진 않을 거야
And there's more.
다른 것도 알아냈어
하나는 호그와트에 있는 것 같아
One of them is at Hogwarts.
What?
뭐?
You saw it?
- 그걸 본 거야?
- 그래. 로웨나 래번클로도 있었어
I saw the castle.
And Rowena Ravenclaw.
It must have something to do with her.
분명 그녀와 연관이 있을 거야
당장 호그와트로 가야 해!
We have to go there, now!
그럴 순 없어!
그게 진짜인 줄 어떻게 알고? 또 계획은?
Well, we can't do that!
We've got to plan,
we've got to figure it out!
Hermione, when have any of
our plans ever actually worked?
헤르미온느, 우리가 세운 계획이
어디 생각대로 된 적 있어?
We plan, we get there,
all hell breaks loose.
계획 짜는 족족
다 저승 갈 뻔 했잖아
He's right!
One problem...
그건 그렇고 지금은 스네이프가 교장인데
정문으로 당당히 갈 순 없는 노릇이잖아
Snape's Headmaster now,
we can't just move from the front door!
Well, we'll go to Hogsmeade,
그래서 "호그스미드"로 갈 거야
지하 비밀 창고로 들어가자
to Honeydukes.
Take the secret passage in the cellar.
It's...
그나저나 그 자가 뭔가 이상해
예전에는 그의 생각 깊은 곳까지 읽을 수 있었는데‥‥
There's something wrong with him.
It's like, you know,
in the past...
I've always been able
to follow his thoughts.
And now everything just feels disconnected.
이제는 연결 돼 있단 느낌이 안 들어
Maybe it's the Horcruxes.
Maybe he's growing weaker.
호크룩스 때문이겠지
그가 죽어가고 있는 거야
Maybe he's dying!
No!
아니야
No, it's.. it's more like he's wounded.
그건 아니고 마치‥‥
상처를 입은 것 같아
If anything, he feels more dangerous.
뭐가 됐던 더 위험해진 건 확실해
소년이 우리의 비밀을 알았구나, 내기니
허점이 드러났다
전력을 쏟아 그를 찾아야만 한다
그리고 너는 항상 내 곁에 있거라
- 경보가 울렸어!
- 여기에 해리 포터가 있다!
- Right here. Come on!
- Search everywhere.
Go, move!
Faster!
해리 포터!
In here, Potter.
여기다, 포터
Come on, move!
Did you look at him?
방금 봤어?
- For a second I thought that was...
- I know. Dumbledore!
- 그 사람 마치‥‥
- 알아. 덤블도어처럼 생겼지
Harry?
해리?
해리, 이거 너잖아
I can see you in this.
Bloody fools, what were you thinking, coming here?
무모하긴! 여기엔 왜 온 거냐?
얼마나 위험한지는 알고 온 게냐?
Have you any idea how dangerous it is?
You're Aberforth, Dumbledore's brother.
당신이 애버포스군요
덤블도어의 동생이시죠
It's you who I've been seeing in here.
전에 본 적 있어요
우리에게 도비를 보내셨죠!
You're the one who sent Dobby.
- Why've you left him?
- He's dead.
그래 도비는 어디 있지?
죽었어요
Sorry to hear it.
I liked that elf.
안됐구나
좋은 요정이었는데
Who gave that to you?
- 저 거울은 어디서 난 거죠?
- 거울 말이냐?
The mirror?
Mundungus Fletcher, 'bout a year ago.
1년 전쯤에 먼던구스에게서 받았지
Dung had no right selling that to you.
It belongs to...
- 먼던구스가 줄만한 게 아녜요. 이건‥‥
- 시리우스거였지
Sirius...
Albus told me.
알버스가 말해줬다
He also told me you'd likely be hacked off,
네가 그걸 보면 길길이 날뛸 거라 말해주더구나
하지만 내가 도와주지 않았더라면 넌 어디 있었을까?
...if you ever found that I had it.
But, ask yourself;
Where would you be if I didn't?
Do you have any others much?
기사단에서 들어온 소식은 없나요?
From the Order?
The Order's finished.
기사단은 전멸했다
You-Know-Who's won,
누가 승리했는지 알 텐데
...anyone who says otherwise
is killing themselves.
그 자를 반대하던 사람들은 다 죽었어
We need to get into Hogwarts, tonight.
오늘 밤 호그와트에 들어갈 거예요
Dumbledore gave us a job to do.
덤블도어가 임무를 줬어요
Did he now...
그랬더냐? 열심히 해라
무지 쉬운 일이군
Nice job?
Easy?
We've been hunting Horcruxes.
우린 호크룩스를 찾고 있어요
And we think the last one's inside
the castle.
그 중 하나가 어디 있는지 알았구요
당신 도움이 필요해요
But we'll need your help getting in.
Which job my brother has given you no,
it's a suicide mission.
그건 임무가 아니라 자살 행위야!
Do yourself a favor, boy.
Go home!
스스로를 아끼거라, 꼬마야
오래 살고 싶거든 집으로 돌아가렴
Live a little longer.
Dumbledore trusted me to see this through.
덤블도어는 우리를 믿어줬어요!
What makes you think you can trust him?
어째서 덤블도어를 그렇게 믿는 거지?
What makes you think you can believe
anything my brother told you?
어째서 형이 말하는건
죄다 옳다고 생각하는 게야?
And in all the time you knew him...
형이랑 지내던 내내
Did he ever mention my name?
내 이름을 한 번이라도 들어본 적 있더냐?
Did he ever mentioned hers?
저 여자아이에 대해
말한 적이 있더냔 말이다
- Why should he...
- Keep secrets.
- 왜 덤블도어가‥‥
- 비밀로 묻었냐고?
You tell me?
- I trusted him.
- That's a boy's answer.
- 전 덤블도어를 믿어요
- 꼭 어린애처럼 말하는구나
어린애가 그 자를 쓰러트린답시고
단서도 없는 호크룩스나 쫓고 있으니‥‥
A boy goes chasing Horcruxes on the word of
a man who wouldn't even tell him where to start.
You're lying!
넌 허세를 부리고 있는거야
Not just on me, that doesn't matter.
To yourself as well.
그 짓이 무모하다고 생각하는 건
비단 나 뿐만이 아닐게다
That's what a fool does.
You don't strike me as a fool, Harry Potter!
그래도 넌 덜 멍청해 보이니
한 번 더 말해주마
이성을 가지고 행동해라
So, I'll ask you again, there must be a reason.
I'm not interested in what happened
between you and your brother.
당신이랑 덤블도어 사이의 일엔 관심 없어요
I don't care that you've given up.
당신이 이 싸움을 포기하던 말던 상관 없고요
I trusted the man I knew.
난 덤블도어를 믿을 겁니다
We need to get into the castle tonight.
우린 오늘 밤 호그와트에 들어가야 해요
You know what to do.
의지가 확고하구나
Where've you sent her?
어디로 보낸 거죠?
You'll see.
곧 알게 될 게다
Soon enough.
That's your sister, Ariana.
Isn't it?
저 분은 "아리아나" 아닌가요?
당신 여동생 말이에요
She died very young, didn't she?
젊은 나이에 죽었군요
My brother sacrificed many things, Mr. Potter.
내 형은 아리아나를 포함해
많은 걸 희생했지, 포터 군
On his journey to find power.
단지 힘 때문에 말이야
아리아나는 그것 때문에 죽었어
Including Ariana.
And she was devoted to him.
형은 모든 걸 여동생에게 주려 했어
시간만 빼고
He gave her everything,
...but time.
Thank you, Mr. Dumbledore.
고맙습니다, 애버포스씨
He did save our lives twice!
애버포스는 두 번이나 우릴 살려줬어
Kept an eye on us on that mirror.
거울을 통해서 우릴 지켜본 거야
That doesn't seem like someone who's given up!
그건 저항을 포기한 사람의 모습이 아냐!
She's coming back.
돌아오고 있네
What's that with her?
어디 갔다 오는 거지?
Neville!
- 네빌! 너 마치‥‥
- 저승에서 올라온 것 같다고?
- How you look...
- Like hell, I reckon.
이건 아무것도 아냐 시무스가 더 하지
기다려봐 아직 더 오고 있어
This is nothing.
Seamus is worse.
Hey, Ab!
We've got a couple more coming through.
Don't remember this on the Marauder's Map.
이런 통로가 있을 줄이야
That's because it never existed till now.
나머진 다 막혔어
여기가 유일한 비밀 통로야
The seven secret passages were sealed off,
before the start of the year.
This is the only way in or out, now.
The grounds are crawled with Death Eaters and Dementors.
학교 밖은 디멘터들 천지야
How about Mr.Snape as Headmaster?
- 스네이프는 교장이 되고 나서 어때?
- 보기 힘들어
Hardly ever seen.
It's the Carrows who's watch out for.
캐로우 놈들이 보호하고 있거든
Carrows?
캐로우?
Yeah. Brother and sister.
Incharge of discipline.
남매인데 훈육 담당이야
우릴 괴롭히는게 취미지
They like punishment, the Carrows.
They did that to you?
너한테 어떻게 했는데?
Why?
Today's Dark Arts lesson was
practicing the Cruciatus curse.
오늘 어둠의 마법 방어술 수업 주제는
"크루시아투스"였어
On first years.
서로한테 저주를 걸라더군
I refused.
난 수업을 거부했지
Hogwarts has changed.
호그와트는 완전히 변했어
Let's have a bit of fun, shall we?
재미있는 놀이 한 번 해볼까?
Hey, listen up you lot!
얘들아, 너희들이 놀랄 일이 있어
I've for you a surprise.
No more Aberforth's cook gonna help.
애버포스의 요리 이야기로는 더 이상 안 놀라
We'll be surprised if we can digest that.
그걸 다 먹었다면 좀 놀랄지도 모르겠군
- Oh my!
- Harry!
해리 포터!
Get the word out to Remus and the others,
that Harry is back.
리무스랑 다른 사람들한테
해리 포터가 돌아왔다고 전해
Okay, okay!
그만
우리한테 먼저 죽겠네
Let's not kill him before You-Know-Who does.
...Do you read? We've a new weather report.
Lightning has struck. I repeat: Lightning has struck.
기상 속보를 전한다
번개가 쳤다 반복한다 번개가 쳤다
What's the fun, Harry?
재미있지?
Okay.
좋아
우리가 찾아야 할 게 있어
There's something we need to find.
Something hidden here, in the castle.
이 학교에 숨겨져 있는거야
And it may help us to defeat
You-Know-Who.
그걸 찾으면 그 자를 물리칠 수 있어
- Alright, what is it?
- We don't know.
좋았어
어떻게 생겼는데?
나도 몰라
- Where is it?
- We don't know that either.
어디 있는데?
몰라
I realize there's not much to go on.
- 단서가 별로 없어
- 별로가 아니라 완전 없는데?
That's nothing to go on.
I think it has something to do with Ravenclaw.
내 생각에 그건 래번클로와 관련 있어
It'll be small, easily concealed.
아마도 작고 숨기기 쉬운 물건일 거야
Anyone, any ideas?
뭔가 떠오르는 사람 없어?
Well, there's Rowena Ravenclaw's lost diadem.
혹시 로웨나 래번클로의
잃어버린 왕관이 아닐까?
Oh, bloody hell!
Here we go!
쟤 말은 무시해
Lost diadem of Ravenclaw?
래번클로의 잃어버린 왕관 몰라?
Hasn't anyone heard of this?
그 이야기 못들어본 거야?
It's quite famous.
꽤 유명한데‥‥
Yes. But, Luna, it's lost.
알아, 루나
그런데 그건 전설이잖아
For centuries.
There's no person alive today who's seen it.
수 세기 동안 그걸 본 사람은 없어
Excuse me, can someone tell me what bloody diadem is?
잠깐만
그 왕관에 대해서 자세히 얘기해봐
It's a sort of crown.
왕관인데‥‥작은 거야
You know, like a tiara.
Harry!
해리
Hi, there.
어‥‥ 안녕
Six months she doesn't see me and
it's like I'm a frankie first-year.
오랜만에 만난 친오빠한테는
아는 척도 안 하네
I'm her brother!
- She's got lots of them, but she's got only one Harry.
- Shut up, Seamus!
- 너 같은 놈은 많지만 해리는 한 명이잖아
- 닥쳐라, 시무스
What is it, Ginny?
무슨 일이야, 지니?
Snape knows... he knows
that Harry was spotted in Hogsmeade.
스네이프가 알고 있어‥‥
해리 포터가 호그스미드에 나타난 걸 안다고
Many of you are surely wondering,
why I have summoned you at this hour.
너희들을 갑자기 부른 이유에 대해
궁금해하는 사람이 많을 걸로 안다
It's come to my attention,
that earlier this evening...
그 이유는 오늘 저녁에
Harry Potter was sighted in Hogsmeade.
해리 포터가 여기에 나타났기 때문이다
Now...
정숙!
should anyone...
혹시라도
student or staff attempt to aid Mr. Potter?
학생이나 교수들 중에서
해리 포터를 돕는 사람이 있다면
They will be punished in a manner consistent with
the severity of their transcription, further more...
매우 가혹하고 엄격한 처벌을 받게 될 것이며
뿐만 아니라
Any person found to have
knowledge of these events...
누구라도 이와 관련해서 알고 있으나
who fails to come forward...
숨기려 하는 사람은
...will be treated as equally guilty.
해리 포터와
같은 죄로 다스릴 것이다
Another...
따라서
If anyone in here has any knowledge of
Mr. Potter's movements this evening.
너희들 중에서 오늘 밤
포터의 행적에 대해 알고 있는 사람은
I invite them to step forward.
앞으로 나와주길 바란다
Now!
당장
It seems, despite your exhaustive defensive strategies,
스스로를 너무 믿고 있더군
...you still have a bit of security problem, Headmaster.
감시가 허술해진 줄도 모르고 말이야, 교장 선생
I'm afraid it's quite extensive.
이제 상황이 뒤바뀐 것 같은데
How dare you stand where he stood?
어떻게 당신이 그를 배신할 수 있지?
Tell them how it happened that night?
Tell them how you looked him in the eye...
그 날 밤 벌어진 일에 대해서 말해보시지!
당신이 그를 죽인 그 날 말야!
A man who trusted you, and killed him.
당신을 굳게 믿었던 그를 죽인 날을!
Tell them!
말해보라고!
COWARD!!!
겁쟁이!
Harry.
해리‥‥
Potter?
포터 군?
I know that many of you will want to fight.
너희 대부분이 전쟁을 원한다는 걸 알고 있다
Some of you may even think that to fight is wise.
일부는 전쟁만이 현명한 길이라고까지 생각하더군
But this is folly.
멍청한 생각이다
Give me Harry Potter.
해리 포터를 넘겨라
Do this and none shall be harmed.
그러면 아무도 해치지 않겠다
Give me Harry Potter,
and I shall leave Hogwarts untouched.
해리 포터를 넘겨라
그러면 호그와트의 안전은 보장하지
Give me Harry Potter,
and you will be rewarded.
해리 포터를 넘겨라
그러면 큰 상을 받게 될 것이다
You have one hour.
한 시간을 주겠다
What're you waiting for?
Someone grab him!
뭐하고 있어?
해리를 잡아!
Students out of bed!
뭐하는 짓이야!
Students in the corridor!
- 자기 자리로 돌아가지 못해?
- 지금 상황이 어떤지 모르겠어요? 아둔하기는!
They're supposed to be out of bed,
you blithering idiot!
아‥‥ 죄송합니다
Sorry ma'am.
As it happens, Mr. Filch...
어쨌든 때마침 잘 왔어요, 필치 씨
Your arrival is most opportune.
If you would, I would like you please, to lead Miss Parkinson
and the rest of Slytherin house, from the hall.
여기 파킨슨 양과 슬리데린 학생들을
강당에서 데리고 나가세요
Exactly where is it I'll be leading 'em to, ma'am?
정확히 어디로요?
The dungeons would do.
지하감옥이 좋겠군요
따라와, 이 놈들아!
I presume you have a reason for returning, Potter.
포터 군, 돌아온 이유가 있을거라 믿는다
무엇이 필요하지?
What is it you need?
Time, Professor.
As much as you can get me.
시간요
가능한 최대로 시간을 벌어주세요
Do what you have to do.
임무를 완수하렴
I'll secure the castle.
호그와트는 내가 지키마
Potter...
포터 군‥‥
It's good to see you.
다시 보니 반갑구나
It's good to see you too, Professor.
저도요, 교수님
Hold the fort, Neville.
여길 부탁해, 네빌
Harry!
해리!
Hermione and I've been thinking,
it doesn't matter if we find a Horcrux.
헤르미온느랑 내가 생각을 해봤는데
우리가 호크룩스를 찾아도 문제가 있어
What do you mean?
무슨 소리야?
Unless we can destroy it.
우리가 못 부수면?
So, we were thinking...
- 그러니까 우리 생각은‥‥
- 엄밀히 말해 론 생각인데 괜찮은 것 같아
Well, Ron was thinking, it was Ron's idea.
It's completely brilliant.
You destroyed Tom Riddle's diary
with a Basilisk's fang, right?
톰 리들의 일기장을
바실리스크의 이빨로 없앴던 거 기억하지?
Well, me and Hermione did remind
where we might find one.
나랑 헤르미온느가 그걸 찾을게
Okay.
알겠어
그럼 나를 찾을 때 이걸 써
Okay, but take this.
That way, you can find me when you get back.
Where're you going?
넌 어디로 갈 건데?
Ravenclaw common room,
Gotta start somewhere.
래번클로 기숙사로 갈 거야
거기부터 시작해야겠어
Harry!
해리
Let me get this straight, Professor...
제가 잘못들은 건가요, 교수님?
You're actually giving us
permission to do this?
정말로 그걸 하라는 겁니까?
That is correct, Longbottom.
정확하게 들었구나, 롱바텀 군
To blow it up!
Boom!
그걸 터트리라고요?
그래, 터트려!
Wicked!
와우!
But how on earth are we gonna do that?
그런데 그걸 무슨 수로 터트리죠?
Why don't you confer with Mr. Finnigan?
피니간 군과 상의해보는 게 어떨까?
As I recall, he has a particular
proclivity for pyro-technics.
내 기억으론 그 아이가 불꽃놀이에
비상한 재능을 가진 것 같더구나
I can bring it down.
저한테 맡겨주세요
That's the spirit!
Away, you go.
그럼 어서 시작하거라
어서!
You do realize, of course, we can't
keep out You-Know-Who indefinitely.
아시겠지만 그 자를 무한정 막아낼 순 없어요
That doesn't mean
we can't delay him.
어느정도는 버틸 수 있을 겁니다
And his name is Voldemort.
Filius, you might as well use it.
그리고 그 자식 이름은 볼드모트에요
필리우스씨, 당신도 그렇게 부르세요
He's come to try to kill you, either way!
어차피 그 놈은 우릴 죽이려 들 테니!
Piertotum Locomotor.
Hogwarts is threatened.
호그와트가 유래없는 위험에 처했다
Man the boundaries! Protect us.
Do your duty...
가서 우리를 보호해라
우리의 학교를 지켜라!
....to our school.
I've always wanted to use
that spell!
이 주문 꼭 써보고 싶었는데
Protego Maxima
"프로테고 막시마", "피안토 듀리"
"레펠로 이니미고툼"‥‥.
Fianto Duri
Repello Inimigotum
Protego Maxima
Fianto Duri
Repello....
Protego Maxima
Fianto Duri
Repello Inimigotum
Protego Maxima
Harry, wait!
해리, 기다려봐!
I need to talk to you!
- I'm a bit pre-occupied at the moment, Luna.
- You don't know anything where you're going.
- 지금은 얘기할 시간이 없어
- 내 말 좀 들어줘! 거기엔 아무것도 없어!
You're wasting your time!
Look, we'll talk later,
okay, Luna?
- 안 돼. 나중에 얘기하자
- 해리!
- Harry?
- Later.
Harry Potter, you listen to me right now!
- 제발 나중에!
- 해리 포터, 내 말 들어!
Do you remember what Cho said
about Rowena Ravenclaw's diadem?
산 사람은 본 적도 없는 물건이라잖아
그러니 죽은 사람한테 물어봐야 되지 않겠어?
There is not a person alive who's seen it.
It's obvious, isn't it?
We have to talk to someone who's dead.
It's very impressive, isn't it?
인상적이지 않아?
If you've to find her,
you'll find her down there.
여기로 가면 만날 수 있어
- Aren't you coming?
- No.
너는 같이 안 가?
I think it's best if you two talk alone.
나는 안 갈 거야
그 애는 부끄럼을 잘 타거든
She's very shy.
You're the Grey Lady.
당신이 래번클로의 회색 숙녀군요
The ghost of Ravenclaw tower.
I do not answer to that name!
그딴 이름으로 부르지 마!
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
죄송해요! 잠깐만요!
It's Helena, isn't it?
헬레나.. 맞죠?
Helena Ravenclaw,
Rowena's daughter.
로웨나의 딸 헬레나 래번클로 맞잖아요
Are you a friend of Luna's?
너는 루나의 친구니?
Yes.
그래요
And she thought you might be able to help me.
루나가 당신이 나를
도와줄 거라고 했어요
You seek my mother's diadem?
어머니의 왕관을 찾고 있구나?
Yes.
그래요
That's right.
바로 그거예요
Luna is kind.
루나는 참 착한 애야
Unlike so many of the others.
다른 사람과는 다르지
But she was wrong,
I cannot help you!
하지만 그녀가 잘못 안 거야
난 너를 못 도와줘
Wait, please!
잠깐만 기다려요!
I want to destroy it!
난 왕관을 없애야 해요!
They never learn.
결국 죽음을 택했군
Such a pity.
불쌍한 것들
But, my Lord...
주인님
Shouldn't we wait?
더 기다리는 것이‥‥
My Lord!
Begin!
시작해
I thought you want to do it.
Isn't it, Helena?
학교가 망하는 꼴을 보고싶진 않겠죠?
You want to destroy it?
당신도 왕관이 없어지길 원하잖아요
Another swore to destroy it,
many years ago.
과거에도 누군가가
그걸 없애버리겠다고 약속 했었지
A strange boy with a strange name.
이상한 이름을 가진 남자아이였어
Tom Riddle.
톰 리들이죠?
But he lied.
하지만 거짓말이었어
He's lied to many people.
그는 원래 거짓덩어리였어요
I know what he's done!
I know who he is!
그 애는 날 속였어!
분명 너도 똑같겠지!
He defiled it, with dark magic!
그 놈이 어둠의 마법으로
어머니의 왕관을 더럽혔다구!
I can destroy it.
톰 리들은 당신을 속였겠지만 난 안 그래요
왕관이 어디 있는지만 말해줘요
Once and for all.
But only if you tell me
where he hid it?
You do know, where he hid it?
그가 왕관을 어디 숨겼는지 아시잖아요
Don't you, Helena?
그렇죠, 헬레나?
You just have to tell me.
그냥 말해주세요
Please!
제가 없앨게요
Strange!
참 이상하군
You remind me of him a bit.
너는 그 애를 참 닮았단 말야
It's here, in the castle.
왕관은 여기에 있어
In the place where everything is hidden.
모든 걸 숨길 수 있는 그런 장소에 있지
If you have to ask...
물어야 한다면 알 수 없어
스스로 묻기만 하면 찾게 될 거야
....you will never know.
If you know...
...you need only ask.
Thank you!
고마워요
Tell Professor McGonagall.
Remus and I will handle this side of the castle.
여기는 나 혼자 맡는다
자네들은 맥고나걸 교수님을 도와
Yes, sir!
정말로요?
Hey Dean, on second thoughts, tell Professor McGonagall we
might need one or two more wands this side.
아니. 맥고나걸 교수님이
여기에 지원을 보내는 게 낫겠군
It is the quality of one's convictions that determine
his success..
성공을 결정하는 것은
따르는 자의 숫자가 아닌 한 사람의 질이다
...not the number of followers.
Who said that?
어디서 나온 말이야?
Me.
내 머리
You okay, Freddie?
무섭냐, 프레드?
Yeah.
당근이지
Me too.
나도 그래
Harry talks in his sleep.
그거 알아? 해리가 잘 때마다 이 말을 하거든
Do you know this?
No, of course, not!
그걸 내가 어떻게 알아
Yeah?
You and whose army?
멍청이! 꼴 좋다!
You do it.
네가 해
I can't.
- 못하겠어
- 할 수 있어
Yes, you can!
Neville!
네빌!
That went well.
제대로 터졌네
Get inside! This way!
Take cover! Take cover
안으로 피하거라!
Stupefy
"스투페파이"!
Ginny, Neville!
You alright?
지니, 네빌!
괜찮아?
Never better!
I feel like I can spit fire!
말짱해!
힘이 샘솟는 것 같아!
Have you seen Luna up here?
혹시 루나 봤니?
Luna?
I'm mad for her. I think it뭩 about time I told her
since we뭠l probably both be dead by dawn.
루나?
죽기 전에 마지막으로
내 마음을 전하려고!
어서 가봐
I know.
Bloody hell!
We'll never find him on this.
해리를 어떻게 찾아야 하지?
Here he is!
여기 있어!
- Just now...
- Brilliant!
He just vanished.
- 저기서 뭐하는 거야?
- 사라졌어!
I just now I saw it.
Maybe he's gone to the Room of Requirement.
필요의 방에 들어가면 지도에 안보이잖아
It doesn't show up on the map, does it?
You said that last year.
That's right, I....I did.
그래, 저번에도 그랬었지
Let's go.
가자
Brilliant!
똑똑하네
Come on!
움직여!
Well, well...
이런, 이런
What brings you here, Potter?
여기서 뭐하냐, 포터?
I could ask you the same.
너야말로
You have something of mine.
내 걸 가지고 있잖아
I'd like it back.
내 지팡이 내놔
What's wrong with the one you have?
- 그 지팡이는 뭔데?
- 엄마 거야
It's my mother's.
It's powerful, but it's...
좋은 것이지만‥‥
..not the same.
지팡이엔 각자의 주인이 있지
이건 내 말을 잘 안들어
Doesn't quite understand me.
You know what I mean?
무슨 말인지 알아먹어?
Why didn't you tell her?
어째서 그때 벨라트릭스한테
곧바로 말하지 않았지?
Bellatrix?
You knew it was me.
나라는 걸 알았을 텐데
You didn't say anything.
그런데도 넌 말하지 않았어
Come on, Draco!
말포이, 어서 해리를 죽여!
Don't be a prat.
Do it!
Easy!
가만 있어
Expelliarmus
"익스펠리아무스"!
Avada Kedavra
- "아바다 케다브라"!
- "스투페파이"!
Stupefy
This is my girlfriend,
you bloody gits!
내 여친 건들지 마!
Got it!
잡았다!
살려줘! 빨리 도망 가!
고일이 불을 내뿜어!
They've set the bloody place on fire!
Come on!
This way!
서둘러! 이쪽이야!
쟤네들 구해줘야 돼!
We can't leave them!
He's joking, right?
미친 거 아니야?
구하다가 우리가 죽으면
그땐 내가 널 죽일 거야!
If we die for them,
Harry, I'm gonna kill you!
Harry!
해리!
My Lord?
Avada Kedavra!
주인님?
"아바다 케다브라"!
Come Nagini, I need to keep you safe.
내기니, 너만은 안전해야 한다
It's the snake....
그 뱀이야
....and she's the last one.
뱀이 마지막 호크룩스였어
It's the last Horcrux.
Look inside him, Harry.
그 놈의 머릿속으로 들어가봐
거기에 뱀도 같이 있을 거야
Find out where he is,
if you find him, we can find the snake.
And we can end this!
이 싸움을 끝낼 수 있어!
My Lord...
주인님
Might it be less...
주제넘게 끼어들어서 죄송하지만
I should not be more prudent to call off
this attack.
꼭 전쟁을 할 필요가 있었을까요?
Simply seek the boy.
해리 포터만 찾으시면 끝날 일입니다
Yourself.
I do not need to seek the boy...
내가 해리 포터에게 가는 것이 아니다
....before the night is out, he will come to me!
Do you understand?
이 밤이 지나기 전에
그 녀석은 제발로 찾아 온다! 알겠느냐?
Look at me!
나를 보거라
How can you live with yourself, Lucius?
루시우스, 그렇게 자신감이 없어서
어찌 살아가겠느냐?
I don't know.
죄송합니다
Go and find Severus.
스네이프를 찾아서
Bring him to me.
내게 데려와
I know where he is.
어디 있는지 알겠어
Come on!
No!
안 돼!
You have performed extra-ordinary magic
with this wand, My Lord,
주인님...
지팡이의 힘은 이미 입증되지 않았습니까?
...in the last few hours alone.
No!
아니
No! I am extra-ordinary.
But the wand resists me.
아니야 내 본래의 힘이 강한 것 뿐
지팡이는 여전히 나를 거부해
There is no wand more powerful.
Ollivander himself has said it.
더 강력한 지팡이는 없습니다
올리밴더가 그렇게 말했잖습니까
Tonight, when the boy comes.
It will not fail you, I am sure of it...
오늘 밤 그 지팡이로 해리 포터를
없앨 수 있을거라 장담합니다
It answers to you,
and you only.
지팡이는 주인님 것입니다
Does it?
그런가?
My Lord?
확실합니다
The wand, does it truly
answer to me?
하지만 여전히 지팡이가 날 거부한다
You're a clever man, Severus.
스네이프, 넌 참 영리한 놈이야
Surely you must know...
분명 너는 알고 있어
- Where does its true loyalty lie?
- With you...
나에 대한 충성심은 어디 간 거지?
제 충성심은 주인님께 있습니다
Of course, My Lord.
The Elder Wand cannot serve me properly,
because I am not its true master.
지팡이가 내 말을 듣지 않았어
나를 주인으로 여기지 않는 거라구
The Elder Wand belongs to the
wizard who killed its last owner.
지팡이는 전 주인을 이긴
마법사를 섬기게 되어있지
You killed Dumbledore, Severus.
덤블도어를 죽인 건 너잖아, 세베루스
While you live, the Elder
Wand cannot truly be mine.
네가 살아있는 한
지팡이는 내 것이 될 수 없어
You've been a good and faithful servant,
Severus.
너는 충실하고 믿음직한 부하였다
But only I can live forever.
하지만 오직 나만이
영원히 살 권리가 있지
My Lord...
주인님?
Nagini, kill!
내기니, 죽여라
Take it...
Take it up, please!
해리, 내 눈물을 받거라
아무 병이나 줘 봐
눈물을 담을 수 있는 걸로!
Give me something!
Quickly, a flask. Anything!
Take them to the Pensieve.
그걸 펜시브에 뿌려라
Look at me...
날 보거라
You really have your mother's eyes.
네 엄마 눈을 꼭 닮았구나
You've fought valiantly,
but in vain...
고작 한 사람 때문에 이렇게 되었구나
내게 저항하면 죽음 뿐이라는 걸 이제 알았으리라 믿는다
I do not wish this. Every drop of magical blood
spilled is a terrible waste.
무고한 마법사들이 피를 흘리는 걸 원치 않는다
I, therefore command my forces to retreat...
그리하여 나는 군대를 무르기로 결정했다
In their absence,
dispose your dead with dignity,
Harry Potter, I now speak directly to you.
해리 포터, 지금부터 너에게만 말하겠다
On this night, you have allowed your friends to die
for you, rather than face me yourself.
친구들을 죽음으로 내모는 것이 즐겁지 않으면
나에게로 오라. 명예롭게 싸워라
There is no greater dishonor.
Join me in the Forbidden Forrest...
금지된 숲으로 와서 네 운명을 받아들여라
...and confront your fate.
If you do not do this, I shall kill every last man,
woman and child who tries to conceal you from me.
제안을 거부하면 그 누구든 상관없이
너를 보호하고자 하는 이들을 모조리 죽일 것이다
Where's everybody?
다들 어디 있지?
Harry?
왔느냐
Oh, come on!
Don't be sad on it, she's passed.
살리기엔 너무 늦었구나
There, she's gone.
넌 괴물이야!
엄마한테 다 이르겠어
Freak! Come here! I'm gonna tell mommy!
You're freak!
릴리, 넌 괴물이야!
You're freak, Lily!
Come here!
She's jealous.
She's ordinary and you're special.
그 애는 널 시기하는 거야
걘 평범하지만 넌 특별하니까
그 말이 맞아, 세베루스
That's not true, Severus.
Gryffindor!
그리핀도르!
- Hi, I'm James.
- Hi, I'm Lily.
- 안녕, 난 제임스라고 해
- 안녕, 난 릴리야
- 너도 네 아비 제임스랑 똑같아. 게으르고 오만하지!
- 아버지를 욕하지 마!
Just like your father.
Don't say a word against my father!
주인과 그 종복들이 다시 합쳐지리니!
Masters shall be reunited once more!
Severus.
세베루스 스네이프?
No, don't kill me!
날 죽이지 마세요‥‥
The prophecy did not refer to a woman.
그 여자를 아직 잊지 못하는구나
It spoke about a boy born at the end of the July.
- 예언은 7월 말에 태어난 아기에 대해 언급하고 있네
- 알고 있습니다. 그 아이는 릴리의 아들이예요!
Yes, but he thinks it's her son!
He intends to hunt them down and
to kill them.
그 자는 그들을 죽일 겁니다
Hide him... hide them all.
I beg you!
아이를 숨겨야 합니다. 그들 모두를 숨겨야 해요
제발 부탁입니다!
What would you give me in exchange, Severus?
그 대가로 뭘 줄 건가, 세베루스?
- Anything.
- Harry...
어떤 것이든 바치죠
Harry, you were so loved.
해리, 우린 너를 무척 사랑한단다
너무 사랑스러워
엄마는 너를 언제나 생각한단다
So loved!
Harry, mama loves you.
Dadda loves you.
아빠도 너를 사랑할 거야
Harry, be safe.
해리, 너는 살아남아야 해
Be strong.
강해지거라
Avada Kedavra!
"아바다 케다브라"!
You said you would keep her safe.
그녀가 안전할 거라 했잖습니까?
Lily and James...
릴리와 제임스는
..put their faith in the wrong person,
Severus.
잘못된 적수를 만났어, 세베루스
Rather like you.
자네처럼 말이야
The boy survives.
아이는 살아남았네
He doesn't need protection,
the Dark Lord has gone.
그 아이는 보호가 필요 없어요
어둠의 제왕은 사라졌단 말입니다!
The Dark Lord will return.
어둠의 제왕은 돌아올 걸세!
And when he does, the boy
will be in terrible danger!
어둠의 제왕이 돌아오면
그 아이는 큰 위험에 처할 거야
He has her eyes.
아이가 엄마 눈을 꼭 닮았더군
If you truly loved her...
자네가 진정 릴리를 사랑했다면‥‥
No one, can know.
제 임무는 비밀로 해주십시오
I shall never reveal the best of you,
Severus.
비밀은 들키지 않을 걸세, 세베루스
Your word?
약속하신 겁니다
Can you risk your life every day
to protect the boy?
자네는 그 아이를 보호하기 위해서
목숨을 내놓을 각오가 돼 있나?
... He possesses no measurable talent, his arrogance rivals even that of his father
and he seems to relish in his fame...
그 아이는 엄청난 능력을 지녔죠‥‥
하지만 그걸 자만하고 있어요
Don't say a word against my father!
- 아버지를 욕하지 마!
- 제임스 포터, 게으르고 건방진 놈‥‥
James Potter, lazy, arrogant.
- My father was a great man!
- Your father was a swine!
- 내 아버지는 위대한 분이셨어!
- 네 아비는 쓰레기였어!
Drink it, it will contain the curse to
your hand, for the time being.
이걸 드세요
손에 저주가 걸렸군요
- It will spread, Albus.
- How long?
- 곧 온몸으로 퍼질 겁니다
- 얼마나 살 수 있겠나?
Maybe a year.
1년 정도
Don't ignore me, Severus.
기다리게 스네이프
볼드모트는 말포이에게 날 죽이라고 시킬 걸세
We both know Lord Voldemort has ordered
the Malfoy boy to murder me.
But should he fail, I should presume
the Dark Lord will turn to you.
말포이가 나를 못 죽이면
필시 자네에게 임무를 넘기겠지
You must be the one to kill me, Severus.
그러니 자네가 나를 죽여야 하네
It is the only way.
그게 유일한 방법이네
Only then, will the Dark Lord trust you completely.
그래야만 어둠의 제왕이
자네를 완전히 믿게 돼
It will come a time, when Harry Potter,
must be told something.
때가 되면 해리에게 전할 것이 있네
But you must wait, until Voldemort is at his
most vulnerable.
하지만 자넨 볼드모트가
가장 약해질 때까지 기다려야 해
Must be told what?
뭘 전한다는 겁니까?
On the night, Lord Voldemort went
to Godric's Hollow to kill Harry...
볼드모트가 해리를 죽이러
고드릭 골짜기에 갔던 밤‥
And Lily Potter cast herself between them...
릴리 포터는 해리를 구하기 위해
...the curse rebounded.
볼드모트의 저주를 몸으로 막았지
When that happens, a part of Voldemort's soul...
그때 볼드모트의 영혼 일부가
...latched itself onto the only living thing
it could find...
살아있는 생명 중 가장 가까이 있던
...Harry himself.
해리에게 옮겨 간 거지
그래서 해리가 뱀과 말을 할 수 있는 것이고
There's a reason Harry can speak with snakes...
There's a reason he can look into
Lord Voldemort's mind...
볼드모트의 생각마저 엿볼 수 있게 된 거지
A part of Voldemort lives inside him.
볼드모트의 일부가
해리의 안에서 살아있단 뜻일세
So, when the time comes...
그래서 때가 되면‥‥
...the boy must die?
해리가 죽어야 한다는 건가요?
Yes... yes.
He must die.
그래
죽어야만 해
You've kept him alive, so he can
die at the proper moment?
필요할 때 죽이려고 살려두는 거군요
You've been raising him like a pig for slaughter.
도살할 돼지를 키워서 잡아먹는 것처럼
Don't tell me now, that you've
grown to care for the boy.
해리가 걱정되는 것처럼 말하는군
Expecto Patronum
"익스팩토 패트로눔"
Lily!
릴리의 암사슴‥
After all this time?
아직도 그녀를 사랑하는군
Always.
언제나 그랬습니다
So, when the time comes...
그러니까 때가 되면
...the boy must die?
해리가 죽어야 한다고요?
Yes.
그래
He must die.
And Voldemort himself must do it.
그 애는 죽어야만 하네
반드시 볼드모트가 직접 죽여야 하지
That is essential.
그래야만 해
- Where've you been?
- I thought you went to the forest.
- 어디 갔었어?
- 금지된 숲에 간 줄 알았잖아
I'm going there now.
지금 거기로 갈 거야
Are you mad?
No...
미쳤어? 안 돼!
You can't give yourself up to him.
가면 넌 죽을 거야
What is it, Harry?
무슨 일이야?
What is it you know?
뭔가를 안 거야?
There's a reason I can hear them.
이유가 있었어
The Horcruxes.
내가 마지막 호크룩스인 것 같아
I think I've known for a while.
내가 오래 전부터 느꼈던 거고
And I think you have, too.
너희들도 어렴풋이 알고 있었을 거야
- I'll go with you.
- No, kill the snake.
- 나도 갈래
- 안 돼, 너희는 뱀을 처리해
Kill the snake, and then it's just him!
뱀만 죽이면 다 끝나
[나는 끝에서 열린다]
I'm ready to die.
나는 죽을 각오가 됐어
부활의 돌‥
Resurrection Stone.
You've been so brave, sweetheart.
정말 용감하구나, 아들아
Why are you here?
All of you.
어떻게 나타나신 거죠?
We never left.
우린 네 곁을 떠난 적이 없단다
Does...
시리우스, 죽는 거 아프지 않아요?
Does it hurt?
Dying?
Quicker than falling asleep.
잠드는 거랑 비슷해
너무 걱정 마라, 아들아
You're nearly there, son.
I'm sorry.
죄송해요
I never wanted any of you to die for me.
저 때문에 부모님이 죽는 걸 원치 않았어요
리무스씨, 당신 아들은‥
And, Remus, your son?
Others will tell him what his
mother and father died for.
사람들이 내가 어떻게 자랑스럽게 죽었는지 말해주겠지
언젠가 너도 알게 될 거야
One day, he'll understand.
제 곁에 계실 거죠?
You'll stay with me?
Until the end.
언제까지나
And he won't be able to see you?
항상 이렇게 볼 수 있겠죠?
No.
아니. 우린 네 마음 속에 있을 거란다
We're here, you see.
Stay close to me.
꼭 붙들고 계세요
언제까지든
Always.
No sign of him, My Lord.
주인님, 녀석이 오지 않습니다
I thought he would come.
올 거라고 믿었거늘
Harry, no!
- 해리냐? 안 돼! 여긴 왜 온 거야?
- 입 닥쳐!
- What're yeh doin' here?
- Quiet!
Harry Potter...
해리 포터
...The Boy Who Lived...
살아남은 아이
...come to die.
죽으러 왔구나
Avada Kedavra
"아바다 케다브라"!
You can't help...
불쌍히 여길 필요 없다
그가 자초한 일이니까
Harry, you wonderful boy...
You brave, brave man!
넌 정말 용감했다
좀 걷자꾸나
Let us walk.
교수님, 저건 뭐죠?
Professor, what is that?
볼드모트 영혼의 일부란다
Something beyond either of our help.
A part of Voldemort sent here to die.
죽어서 여기로 보내진 거지
여기가 어딘지 아세요?
And exactly where are we?
내가 묻고 싶은 말이구나
여기가 어딘 것 같으니?
I was going to ask you that.
Where would you say that we are?
킹스 크로스역 같은데요
Well, it looks like King's Cross station.
좀 더 깨끗하고‥
Only cleaner...
....and without all the trains.
기차가 없는 것만 빼면요
King's Cross, is that right?
그렇구나
This is, as they say, 'your' party.
전에 말했듯이 여긴 네 기억 속이란다
I expect you now realize that
you and Voldemort...
나는 네가 볼드모트와
고드릭 골짜기에서 엮인 그 날 밤부터
...have been connected by something other than fate.
Since that night in Godric's Hollow,
all those years ago.
인연이 아닌 다른 무언가로
연결 돼 있단 생각을 했지
So it's true then, sir.
그의 일부분이 제 안에 있는 거죠? 그렇죠?
A part of him lives within me, doesn't it?
그랬지
Did.
It's been just destroyed many moments
ago by none other than Voldemort himself.
오랜 시간이 지나면서
네 안의 볼드모트는 죽었다시피 했단다
You, were the Horcrux he
never meant to make, Harry.
너는 볼드모트가 의도하지 않은 호크룩스였어
- I have to go back, haven't I?
- Oh, that's up to you.
- 저는 돌아가야 하나요?
- 그건 너에게 달렸다
- I've a choice?
- Oh, yes!
- 제가 선택을 할 수 있는 건가요?
- 그렇고 말고
We're in King's Cross, you say.
네 말처럼 우린 킹스 크로스역에 있단다
네가 맘먹기에 따라 기차도 탈 수 있겠지
I think if you so decide,
you'll be able to board a train.
And where would it take me?
기차는 어디로 향하죠?
On.
타 봐
Voldemort has the Elder Wand.
볼드모트가 딱총나무 지팡이를 가지고 있죠?
그렇지
True.
And the snake's still alive?
- 뱀도 아직 살아있고요?
- 그래
Yes.
그럼 전 아무것도 한게 없네요
And I've nothing to kill it with?
Help will always be given at Hogwarts, Harry.
호그와트는 도움이 필요한 사람을 도와준단다
To those who ask for it.
I've always pride of myself
on my ability to turn a phrase.
난 언제나 내 표현 방법에 감탄하곤 하지
Words are, in my not so humble opinion...
아무리 쓸 데 없는 말이라도
무한한 마력만큼이나
..are most inexhaustible source of magic.
사람을 다치게 하거나 치유할 수 있단다
Capable of inflicting injury and remedies.
But I would in this case...
하지만 내 원래 관점대로 말하자면
...amend my original statement to this:
Help, will always be given at Hogwarts,
호그와트는 도움을 받을
가치가 있는 사람만을 도와준단다
To those who deserve it.
Do not pity the dead, Harry...
죽음을 슬퍼하지 말거라
Pity the living.
살아있는 사람을 불쌍히 여기거라
And above all...
그리고 무엇보다도
....all those who live without love.
사랑 없이 살아가는 사람을
가장 불쌍히 여겨라
Professor, my mother's Patronus...
교수님, 제 어머니의 패트로누스는‥
...was a doe, wasn't it?
암사슴이었어요
As the same as Professor Snape's.
스네이프 교수님처럼요
It's curious, don't you think?
참 이상하지 않나요?
Actually, if I think about it...
글쎄다. 내가 생각하기에는
그리 이상한 일은 아닌 것 같구나
...it doesn't seem curious at all!
I'll be going now, Harry.
이만 가봐야겠다
교수님
Professor?
이건 현실인가요?
Is this all real?
아니면 제 꿈 속 인가요?
Or is it just happening inside my head?
Of course it's happening
inside your head, Harry.
당연히 너의 무의식이 만든 공간이란다
현실이라고는 말 못하겠구나
Why should that mean, that it's not real?
Professor?
교수님
What should I do?
어디 가세요?
Professor!
교수님!
My Lord, My Lord...
Are you hurt?
주인님, 괜찮으세요?
I don't need your help.
네 도움은 필요 없어
주인님‥‥
The boy...
죽었느냐?
Is he dead?
Is he alive?
우리 말포이는 살아있니?
Draco, is he alive?
죽었습니다
Dead.
해그리드가 안고 있는 게 누구야?
Who is that?
Hagrid's carrying?
네빌, 누구야?
Neville, who is it?
해리 포터는
Harry Potter...
죽었다!
... is dead!
- No!
안 돼!
No!
Silence!
닥쳐라!
어리석은 계집!
Stupid girl!
Harry Potter...
해리 포터는
죽었다잖느냐
...is dead!
From this day forth...
지금 이 순간부터
내가 너희들의 주인이다
...you'll put your faith in me.
해리 포터가 죽었다!
Harry Potter is dead!
어서 나에게 와서 충성을 맹세해라
And now it's the time to declare yourself.
앞으로 나와 나의 편에 서라
Come forward and join us...
아니면 죽음 뿐이다
...or die!
드레이코
Draco!
드레이코 말포이
Draco.
얘야
어서 이리 오너라
Come.
잘했다 드레이코!
Well done, Draco.
Well done!
장하구나!
이젠 절름발이까지 나에게 오는군
Well, I must say I'd hoped for better.
네 이름은 뭐지?
And who might you be, young man?
네빌 롱바텀
Neville Longbottom.
Well, Neville, I'm sure we can
find a place for you in our rank.
그래 네빌 너한테 딱맞는
자리를 주도록 하지
할 말이 있다
I'd like to say something.
여기 있는 사람들 모두
네가 무슨 얘길 할지 궁금해 하는구나
Well, Neville, I'm sure we'd all be
fascinated to hear what you have to say.
- Doesn't matter that Harry is gone.
- Stand down, Neville!
- 해리가 죽은 것과는 상관 없어
- 그만해, 네빌!
사람들이 매일 죽어나갔다고!
People die everyday!
Friends, family.
친구랑 가족들‥
그래
Yeah...
We lost Harry tonight.
오늘은 해리도 죽었지
하지만 해리는 아직 살아있어
He's still with us.
내 마음 속에 말야
In here.
So as Fred, Remus...
프레드랑 리무스‥
통스‥
Tonks...
모두 내 마음 속에 살아있어
All of them.
그들의 죽음은 헛된 게 아냐
They didn't die in vain.
하지만 당신은‥
But you will.
Because you're wrong!
당신은 틀렸어!
해리의 정신은 우리에게 남아있다고!
Harry's heart did beat for us.
우리 모두에게 말이야!
For all of us!
It's not over!
Confringo
뭐하는 거야, 이놈들아!
돌아와서 싸우지 못해!
Come on!
모두 성 안으로 들어가!
All remain into the castle.
- 뱀을 죽여야 해
- 바실리스크의 이빨을 가져가
We have to kill the snake.
Neville!
- 네빌!
- 안 돼!
내 딸은 안 돼!
이 망할 년아!
Not my daughter, you bitch!
당신 말이 맞아‥
Hey, you were right...
스네이프에게 그 지팡이가
널 거부한다고 말했잖아
...when you told Professor Snape
that wand was failing you.
항상 지팡이는‥
It will always fail...
- 그래서 스네이프를 죽였지!
- 근데 지팡이의 주인이 그가 아니었다면?
I killed Snape!
But what if the wand never belonged
to Snape?
다른 사람이 주인이라면?
What if its allegiance is always
to someone else?
톰 리들
Oh, come on, Tom...
그 때 그 날 처럼 끝을 내볼까?
Let's finish this the way we started.
우리 둘이서!
Together!
Die!
지팡이를 놓고 온 줄 알았는데 주머니에 있더래
해리
Harry!
왜 딱총나무 지팡이가
볼드모트의 말을 듣지 않았지?
Why didn't it work for him?
The Elder Wand?
진짜 주인은 다른 사람이었어
It answered to somebody else.
볼드모트가 스네이프를 죽이려 했을 때
그는 지팡이가 스네이프의 소유라고 생각했지만
When he killed Snape, he thought
the wand would become his.
But the thing is...
The wand never belonged to Snape.
지팡이는 스네이프의 것이 아니었어
처음에 덤블도어를
무장해제시킨 사람은 말포이였어
It was Draco, who disarmed Dumbledore
that night in the Astronomy tower.
그 순간부터 딱총나무 지팡이는
말포이의 것이었지
From that moment on and the wand
answered him,
말포이를 무장해제시킨 건 나였고
Until, the other night when I disarmed Draco.
At Malfoy Manor.
그 말은‥
So, that means...
내 것이지!
It's mine!
- 이제 그건 어떻게 하지?
- 뭐?
- What should we do with it?
- We?
딱총나무 지팡이 말이야
Just saying, that's the Elder Wand.
세상에서 가장 강력한 지팡이라고
The most powerful wand in the world.
그것만 있으면 너는 무적이야
With that, he'd be invincible.
19년 후
같이 갈까?
Together.
- 가방 챙겼지?
- 네
- Bag?
- Yeah.
외투도 잘 입고
Jumper?
보고 싶을 거야
I'm gonna miss you.
저기 오네
Here they come.
Dad?
아빠
제가 슬리데린에 배정 되면 어떡하죠?
What if I am put in Slytherin?
알버스 세베루스 포터
네 이름은 호그와트 두 교장의
이름을 따서 지었단다
Albus Severus Potter.
You were named after two Headmasters of Hogwarts.
한 분은 슬리데린 출신이었고
아주 용감한 분이었단다
One of them was a Slytherin.
And he was the bravest man I've ever known.
- But just say if I am...
- Then Slytherin house...
- 아빠 말은 제가 만약‥
- 슬리데린은 아주 멋진 마법사를 얻는 거지
...will have gained a wonderful young wizard.
But listen...
네가 진정 그리핀도르로 가고 싶다면
그렇게 될 거야
If it really means that much to you,
you can choose Gryffindor.
The Sorting Hat takes
your choice into account.
모자가 너의 선택을 존중해줄 테니까
- Really?
- Really.
- 진짜요?
- 그렇고 말고
- Ready?
- Ready.
- 준비 됐니?
- 됐어요
감독 : 데이빗 예이츠
원작 : 조앤 K. 롤링